Guide to the Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group Records TAM.630
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group Records
2011-2013
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Roberts, Amy
Occupy Wall Street (Movement)
Occupy Wall Street. Archives Working Group.
TAM.630
144 Linear Feet in 33 oversize flat boxes, 9 flat file folders, 19 custom boxes, 4 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, and 2 media boxes
51 Megabytes in 47 graphics
The Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group was created in October 2011 by Amy Roberts and Jeremy Bold to collect and preserve material related to the Occupy Wall Street protest in the fall of 2011 in Manhattan, New York. The Archives Working Group (AWG) continued to collect materials related to other Occupy protests in 2012 and 2013, as well as climate change and racial justice protests. The Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group Records document protests by the Occupy movement between 2011 and 2013, and the work of the AWG to collect materials from these protests. The collection also documents the beginning of the AWG through mission statements, draft budget proposals, meeting agenda, and minutes. The bulk of the collection documents the first Occupy Wall Street protest in the fall of 2011 in Zuccotti Park in Manhattan through posters, artwork, fliers, clippings from print and online news sources, letters of support, diaries, born-digital photographs, buttons, textiles, organizational documents, and the movement's newsletter, The Occupied Wall Street Journal.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction, with the exception of textiles, select artwork, and larger than 24" x 36" signs.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Amy Roberts of the Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group, 2013 and 2017. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2013.010, 2013.022, 2017.048, and 2017.077. Materials associated with the collection were found in repository in April 2014. The accession number associated with this material is 2014.096.
Appraisal
In 2017, duplicates fliers and periodicals were deaccessioned.
In May 2018, the following materials were removed from the collection: foam letters, clothing, drums and drumsticks, candles, markers, heat blankets, and zip-tie handcuffs. Also removed were posters with duplicative, general, or personal messages; abstract artwork; blank cardboard; and extremely dirty or damaged posters.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged by type of document. The container list is arranged in alphabetical order.
Posters collected on specific dates are listed in chronological order by collection date, with descriptive information about each sign included in the inventory. Posters for which there is no information about when they were collected are not arranged, but are housed according to size and material type.
Discussion documents are arranged in alphabetical order by discussion topic. The remaining organizational documents are not arranged, but are housed according to size.
Historical Note
The Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group was created in October 2011 by Amy Roberts and Jeremy Bold to collect and preserve material related to the Occupy Wall Street (OWS) protest in the fall of 2011 in Manhattan, New York. The Archives Working Group (AWG) was created to enable the movement to document itself and ensure that materials from the movement would be made available to the public. The AWG collected records of the movement in all formats, and documented the decisions of the OWS General Assembly, Spokes Council, and other working groups. The AWG continued to collect materials related to other Occupy protests in 2012 and 2013, as well as climate change and racial justice protests held in New York City during those years.
Custodial History
Materials were collected by Amy Roberts of the Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group in 2011 and transferred to the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives in 2013 and 2017. Materials associated with collection were found in the repository in April 2014 and were accessioned at that time.
Scope and Contents
The Occupy Wall Street Archives Working Group Records document protests by the Occupy movement between 2011 and 2013, and the work of the Archives Working Group (AWG) to collect materials from these protests. The bulk of the collection documents the first Occupy Wall Street (OWS) protest in the fall of 2011 in Zuccotti Park in Manhattan, New York. Materials include posters, fliers, artwork, clippings from print and online news sources, letters of support, diaries, periodicals, pamphlets, music, born-digital photographs, material from the Occupy Wall Street Library, stickers, buttons, textiles with protest slogans, notebooks, correspondence, organizational documents, and the movement's newsletter, The Occupied Wall Street Journal. The ephemera, clippings, pamphlets, and periodicals document Occupy, climate change, and racial justice protests in New York, Massachusetts, and Pennsylvania.
The posters were created by members of the OWS movement in Zuccotti Park in 2011 and document the main issues of the movement, in particular income inequality, wealth distribution, and the influence of corporations on the government. The ephemera, clippings, and periodicals document Occupy, climate change, and racial justice protests in New York, Massachusetts, and Pennsylvania. The ephemera includes buttons, fliers, and posters. Artwork includes large and small scale pieces, including two one dollar bills with protest slogans stamped on them, casino chips with protest slogans, and posters. The letters of support are letters from friends and family of the members of OWS in Lower Manhattan, supporters from across the country, and one seventh grade social studies class in New Jersey. Some of the letters contained financial donations, food, gift cards, and other items supporters thought may be of use to the members of the movement. The diaries contain personal entries and meeting notes created by unidentified members of the Occupy movement. The notebooks were found in Zuccotti Park after a raid on the protesters by the New York Police Department in November 2011 and collected by members of the Archives Working Group.
The organizational documents include a draft vision statements, a "Declaration of the Occupation of New York City", meeting agenda and notes, discussion documents, and notes taken by Amy Roberts at working group meetings. The discussion documents consist of large, rolled sheets of paper with a general topic of discussion and related topics written on the paper. Post-it notes with responses were attached to these papers, presumably by members of the General Assembly. The working groups documented in this collection, include the Archives Working Group and the Music Working Group, with some unspecified working groups. The born-digital photographs depict protesters and police officers, the signs provide information for members of the protest, and the music is a CD with the song "People's Park".
Material documenting the AWG includes mission statements, draft budget proposals, meeting agenda, minutes, and notes. The bulk of the AWG records consist of notes taken by Roberts at AWG meetings, with other material consisting of budget proposals presented to the OWS General Assembly and notes on collecting oral histories and archives best practices.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Textiles, select artwork, and larger than 24" x 36" signs require conservation treatment before they can be made available to researchers.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Occupy movement -- New York (State) -- New York.; Protest movements -- United States.; Picket signs.; Printed ephemera.; Roberts, Amy; Occupy Wall Street. Archives Working Group.
- Artwork, buttons, patches, 2011-2013 (Box 1, Folder 1, Box 4, Folder 10)
- Clippings, 2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- Diaries, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 4, Box 4, Folder 16-18)
- Digital photographs, 2011; 51 Megabytes 47 graphics (Box Electronic records, Object TW_TAM_630_ER_1)
- Flag, 2011 (Flat-file-folder 5)
- Fliers, stickers, and postcards, 2011-2013 (Box 1, Folder 5-13, Box 2, Folder 23, Box 4, Folder 1-4, Folder 10, Box 36, Folder 13-21)
- Letters of support, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 14-23, Box 4, Folder 5-8)
- Organizational documents, 2011-2013 (Box 2, Folder 1-17, Box 4, Folder 11-14, Box 5, Box 11, Box 17, Box 18, Folder 1-3, Box 19, Folder 1, Box 29, Box 31, Box 35, Folder 7-8, Box 36, Folder 10-12, Box 39, Flat-file-folder 4, Flat-file-folder 5, Flat-file-folder 6, Flat-file-folder 7)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Action tactics, 2011 (Box 42)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- [General discussion of movement and its short- and long-term goals], 2011 (Box 48)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Internal coordination, 2011 (Box 43)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Interoccupation communications coordination, 2011 (Box 47)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Narrative message, 2011 (Box 50)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Other, 2011 (Box 43)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Outreach and growth, 2011 (Box 49)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Shared values principles, 2011 (Box 46)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Social and political wins impact, 2011 (Box 41)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Trust relationship building, 2011 (Box 44)
- Organizational documents -- Discussion documents -- Visioning process strategy long term thinking, 2011 (Box 45)
- Pamphlets, 2011-2013 (Box 2, Folder 18-19, Box 4, Folder 15, Box 36, Folder 22-24)
- "People's Park", 2011 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Periodicals, 2011-2013 (Box 2, Folder 20-22, Box 3, Folder 1-4, Box 19, Folder 2, Box 34, Folder 11)
- Poster collected on October 24 -- New survey shows majority of NY'ers support Occupy Wall Street..., 2011 (Box 10)
  Scope and Contents
  11" x 17" White paper with black and red ink, taped to cardboard.
- Poster collected on October 24 -- Show me the $, 2011 (Box 9)
  18.5" x 26.75" Brown cardboard with gold paint.
- Poster collected on October 24 -- Day 1er leaving today to organize other occupations need $$ for smartphone, 2011 (Box 9)
  20" x 23.75" Brown cardboard with black and green marker.
- Poster collected on October 24 -- Occupy Wall Street spends $4,000 a week on photocopies but still cannot buy a coffee machine that keeps the protesters warm, happy and ready to protest, 2011 (Box 10)
  15.25" x 19.5" Brown cardboard with black marker.
- Poster collected on October 24 -- Image of Lloyd Blankfein as vampire drinking the blood of the Statue of Liberty, reads "Enough prosecute Goldman Sachs personhood", 2011 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  14.25" x 22" White poster paper with black marker, and white paper with black ink taped to poster, and silver shoelace. Verso reads: Enough of the vampire squids wrapped around the face of humanity...
- Poster collected on October 24 -- The top 1% controls 40% of wealth, 2011 (Box 9)
  20" x 30" White foamcore with blue, red, green, and black marker. Verso reads: The bottom 40% controls 1% of wealth
- Poster collected on October 24 -- Health care for the 99%, 2011
  25.75" x 26.25" Brown cardboard with black and red marker. Verso reads: Health care not wealth care
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Child safe zone, 2011 (Box 27)
  7.5" x 18" Brown cardboard with black ink and red duct tape.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- A corporation is like a dyslexic Robin Hood, 2011 (Box 27)
  10" x 18" Brown cardboard with red ink.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Life, liberty, and the pursuit of humanity! 99%, 2011 (Box 27)
  14" x 18" Brown cardboard with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Corporate power is big government!, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  9" x 15.75" White cardboard with black marker.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Occupy UES Do it now!, 2011 (Box 27)
  9.5" x 18.5" Brown cardboard with red marker.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Hey! At least North Dakota's hiring!, 2011 (Box 27)
  9.5" x 18.5" Brown cardboard with blue marker.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- There were ninty and nine that safely lay in the shelter of the fold but one was off on hills away buying up all the gold, 2011 (Box 10)
  14" x 20" White paper with black marker on brown cardboard.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Restore American Airlines flight attendants' wages, 2011 (Box 10)
  17" x 19" Brown cardboard with red, green, and blue marker.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- When I play, I draw [Monopoly Commmunity Chest card] When you play, you draw [Monopoly Commmunity Chest card] Why does it feel like we are drawing from different decks?, 2011 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  22" x 28" Orange poster board with black marker and yellow paper with black ink. Verso reads "Corporation: an engenious device for obtaining individual profit without individual responsibility - Ambrose Bierce"
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Give donations to official working groups only, 2011 (Box 28)
  23" x 25.5" Brown cardboard with black marker.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- No left, no right, only 99%, 2011 (Box 39)
  Diameter = 13.5" Blue painted wooden circle with black marker. Verso reads "I don't wanna get locked up but if that's my only choice then so be it!"
- Poster collected on November 4 -- 99% stealing is wrong Cadogan Scimecca 5 years old, 2011 (Box 39)
  Diameter = 13" Blue painted wooden circle with black marker. Verso reads "Do you love yourself or others best?"
- Poster collected on November 4 -- One good way to control greed is to > wages, 2011 (Box 39)
  Diameter = 13.25" Blue painted wooden circle with black marker.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Instead of asking for debt forgiveness, 2011 (Box 39)
  Diameter = 13.25" Blue painted wooden circle with black marker. Verso reads "Stop paying your bills!"
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Sick of big banksters greed + arrogance? Then leave em'! Go with small/local banks + credit unions, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  11" x 14" Yellow poster paper with black marker.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- What do Americans want? Fair pay for hard work, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  11" x 17" White poster paper with red marker. Verso reads "What do banksters want? Freedom to loot
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Eat trees Please pardon our appearance. We are making the world! Feet!, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  11" x 17" White paper with black ink and green marker.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- We are the other 99%, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  12" x 18" Blue poster paper with white and red ink.
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Hungry?, 2011 (Box 27)
  13.25" x 15.5" Black styrofoam with white paint. Verso reads "Eat the rich!"
- Poster collected on November 4 -- You have a gambling problem..., 2011 (Box 27)
  13.5" x 16.5" Black foamcore with white paint. Verso reads "...We're here to help!"
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Justice is blind, 2011 (Box 27)
  13" x 16.5" Black foamcore with white paint. Verso reads "... Not stupid!"
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Forget where the money went..., 2011 (Box 27)
  13.5" x 15.5" Black foamcore with white paint. Verso reads "...Where did it come from??"
- Poster collected on November 4 -- Bail me out! Only $25,000, 2011 (Box 27)
  13.5" x 15.5" Black foamcore with white paint.
- Poster collected on November 6 -- Health care is a human right, 2011 (Box 33)
  18.5" x 21" Brown cardboard with red and blue marker.
- Poster collected on November 6 -- Wall Street you're fired, 2011 (Box 33)
  18" x 19" Brown cardboard with white paper, black ink, blue and red paint, and blue tape.
- Poster collected on November 6 -- Give 2 the people! The G.A. is an evil super power!, 2011 (Box 28)
  7.5" x 30.5" Brown cardboard with white, red, and yellow paint.
- Poster collected on November 6 -- Image of black and white American flag with person lifting one of the stripes, 2011 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  20" x 30" White poster board with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 6 -- Image of person climbing street sign, which reads "Worth fighting for", 2011 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  20" x 30" White poster board with red ink.
- Poster collected on November 6 -- Image of pig, which reads "That's some pig!", 2011 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Poster collected on November 6 -- 99% how many more do we need?, 2011 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  22" x 28" White poster board with brown, red, black, and green paint.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- The Fed-Treasury evil axis rips us all off!, 2011 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  8.5" x 11" White paper with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- We are in a drastic need of ending the exchange of us bonds..., 2011 (Box 36, Folder 1)
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Racism is strictly forbidden here!!, 2011 (Box 27)
  17" x 19" Brown cardboard with purple marker.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Shrewd Uncle Sam..., 2011 (Box 36, Folder 1)
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Wanted Kathleen Ann Corbet, 2011 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  8.5" x 11" White paper with black ink. Verso reads "Wanted Lewis S. Ranieri"
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Image of girl lying on street in front of protesters with "Occupy for innocence", 2011 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  13" x 19" White poster board with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Turn off the news + read!, 2011 (Box 27)
  13" x 18.25" Brown cardboard with black marker.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Elmo hates Wall Street, 2011 (Box 28)
  20" x 29" Brown cardboard with black, brown, and yellow marker.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- First in the nation caucus occupation..., 2011 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  11" x 17" White poster board with black ink and silver duct tape.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Wanted Stanley O'Neal, 2011 (Box 36, Folder 1)
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Wanted Sanford "Sandy" I. Weill, 2011 (Box 36, Folder 1)
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Capitalism Capitalism Capitalism..., 2011 (Box 36, Folder 1)
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Image of a bull surrounded by protesters and bankers, reads "The brazen, brazen bull", 2011 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  14" x 22" Tan paper with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Image of worker confronting evil Uncle Sam, reads "Occupy for freedom peace truth love life", 2011 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  19" x 24.75" White poster board with red and blue paint.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- We, Tamils support Occupy Wall St., 2011 (Box 33)
  12" x 22.5" Brown cardboard with blue marker and twine.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Image of worker confronting evil Uncle Sam, reads "Occupy for freedom peace truth love life", 2011 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  19" x 24.75" White poster paper with blue paint.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Give us back Manhattan, 2011 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  12.5" x 20" Green paper with black ink and blue duct tape.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Money money money no longer funny in a rich mans world, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  12.5" x 20" Green paper with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Int'l. Action Center Occupy Wall Street, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  11" x 17" Yellow paper with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Image of one-eyed Uncle Sam, reads "Stop! These changes are only mandated for your safety, convenience and security!", 2011 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  18" x 24" Grey paper with red paint.
- Poster collected on November 7 -- Image of two hands, reads "Place your hand here. Have stranger place hand here. Remove hands when no longer strangers.", 2011 (Box 33)
  18" x 24" White particleboard with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 9 -- OWS Screen Print Guild..., 2011 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  12" x 18" White paper with black ink, laminated.
- Poster collected on November 9 -- This system has no future for the youth the revolution does! Revcom.us, 2011 (Box 16)
  22" x 29" White foamcore with red and black marker.
- Poster collected on November 9 -- This is just practice, 2011 (Box 10)
  14" x 18" Brown particleboard with black marker.
- Poster collected on November 9 -- Welcome to the United States, Inc, 2011 (Box 15)
  17.5" x 32.5" Brown cardboard with black and white paint.
- Poster collected on November 9 -- #Occupy Life, 2011 (Box 16)
  17.5" x 32.25" Brown cardboard with red paint and black marker.
- Poster collected on November 9 -- The television will not be revolutionized. Let's occupy!!!, 2011
  22.25" x 40.25" Brown cardboard with green paint.
- Poster collected on November 12 -- Save free markets from the Oligarchs and Kleptocrats, 2011 (Box 8)
  20" x 30" Green foamcore with black marker.
- Poster collected on November 12 -- Image of man reading sign, which reads "Occupy Occupy Occupy...", 2011 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  16.75" x 21.5" Paper with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 12 -- Bankers and toffs get stuffed!, 2011 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  20" x 25" Green paper with black ink.
- Poster collected on November 12 -- Image of man eating pie filled with money, titled "American Pie", 2011 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  18" x 23.75" White paper with multi-colored ink. Artist: Michael D'Antuono
- Poster collected on November 12 -- Image of man in suit being comforted by another man, titled "Down & Outsourced", 2011 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  18" x 24" White paper with multi-colored ink. Artist: Michael D'Antuono
- Poster collected on November 12 -- Image of man putting model of United States Capitol building in his pocket, titled "Small Government", 2011 (Box 31, Folder 8)
- Poster collected on November 12 -- Ten years ago we've got Steve Jobs, Bob Hope & Johnny Cash. Now, we've got no jobs, no hope, & no cash, 2011
  26" x 34" Brown cardboard with green, blue, and red crayon
- Poster collected on November 14 -- Image of Michael Bloomberg, police officer, and snowstorm over Zuccotti Park, reads "We have to clear that park before the holidays. Turn the H.A.A.R.P. on full blast!! Let's see them occupy the snow.", 2011 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  22" x 28" White poster paper with pink, purple, and black marker, with clear tape over paper.
- Poster collected on November 14 -- Image of Barack Obama shining a flashlight into a turkey, reads "Hey ho B.O. Where did all our jobs go? Happy thanksgiving everyone, 2011 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  22" x 27.25" White poster paper with black marker.
- Poster collected on November 14 -- Map of United States divided into three sections with numbers in each, reads "Wealth WTF", 2011 (Box 26)
  15.5" x 20.75" White cardboard with black marker.
- Poster collected on November 14 -- Smash the two-party system, 2011 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  12" x 18" White poster paper with black marker. Verso reads: We are the 99%
- Poster collected on November 14 -- For the benefit of the whole..., 2011 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  22" x 28" Yellow poster paper with black and red marker.